罗森受伤了
Ronson's down.
他需要医护救治
He needs medical evac.
硬盘在哪？还在那吗？
Where is it? Is it there?
硬盘不见了
Hard drive's gone.
你确定？
Are you sure?
确定 给我点时间
It's gone. Give me a minute.
肯定是他们拿了 去追
They must have it. Get after them.
我在处理罗森的伤势
I'm stabilizing Ronson.
我们没时间了
We don't have the time.
我要帮他止血！
I have to stop the bleeding!
别管他！
Leave him!
你找到他了吗？
Have you got him?
他在那辆黑色奥迪里面
He's in the black Audi.
罗森怎么样了？
What about Ronson?
他受伤了
He's been hit.
我们会派紧急疏散小组过去
We're sending an emergency evacuation squad.
他们太慢了！
They'll be too bloody late!
他看见我们了
He's seen us.
救护队五分钟内会去救罗森
Medical evac for Ronson five minutes away.
没关系 你用不到它
That's all right. You weren't using it.
另一个我也用不上
I wasn't using that one, either.
趴下
Keep your head down.
快闪开！
Just get clear!
坦纳 怎么走？
Tanner, which way?
继续直走 我会告诉你怎么走
Keep going. I can direct you from here.
你们都知道此次任务的重要性
You both know what's at stake here.
如果名单丢了 后果不堪设想
We can't afford to lose that list.
明白 夫人
Yes, ma'am.
他们现在在哪？
Where are they now?
根据显示 他们应该在集市一带的房顶上
They appear to be on the rooftops of the Grand Bazaar.
从左边走 那有一座桥 你可以拦住他
Take a left. There's a bridge. You can cut him off.
快趴下 先生！
Down, sir!
- 什么情况？- 他们上火车了 夫人
- What happened? - They're on the train, ma'am.
上火车是什么意思？
What do you mean on the train?
我是说 他们在火车顶上
I mean, they're on top of a train.
那就快跟上 别磨蹭！
Well, get after them, for God's sake!
她快跑出监控范围了
She's going out of range.
我们跟踪不到了 我们监视不到那里
We've lost tracking. We're blind here.
- 现在什么情况？- 我还在跟着他们
- What's going on? - I'm still with them.
给我接通闭路电视 人造卫星 任何东西！
Get me CCTV, satellite, anything!
那是什么声音？
What was that?
几辆大众甲壳虫
VW Beetles.
应该是吧
I think.
邦德！他弄断了车厢连接链
Bond! He's uncoupling the cars.
007 你还好吗？
007, are you all right?
刚换了车厢而已
Just changing carriages.
什么情况？快汇报！
What's going on? Report!
情况很复杂 夫人
It's rather hard to explain, ma'am.
007还在继续追捕
007's still in pursuit.
前面没有路了
Looks like there isn't much more road.
我没法继续往下追了
I don't think I can go any further.
我可以开枪
I may have a shot.
但两个人纠缠在一起
It's not clean.
重复 我没法开枪 他们没分开
Repeat, I do not have a clean shot.
前面有个山洞 目标快消失了
There's a tunnel ahead. I'm gonna lose them.
你能找到更好的位置吗？
Can you get into a better position?
找不到 没时间了
Negative. There's no time.
那就开枪
Take the shot.
我说开枪
I said take the shot.
我做不到！我会打到邦德的
I can't! I may hit Bond.
赶快开枪！
Take the bloody shot!
特工受伤了
Agent down.
《007系列之大破天幕杀机》
（伦敦 军情六处）
（讣告：詹姆斯·邦德指挥官 皇家海军三等爵士）
感觉像是被召唤去校长办公室一样
It's like being summoned to the headmaster's study.
是新上任的主席 只是例行公事罢了
It's a new Chairman. Just standard procedure.
要我说这是在浪费我的时间
Bloody waste of my time is what I call it.
我很遗憾我们第一次见面
I'm sorry to have to deal with such.
就要处理这么敏感的话题
a delicate subject at our first encounter.
但是 呃…
But, um…
我必须向你坦白
I have to be frank with you.
我想坦白是最好的办法
I think that would be a good idea.
首相很担心
The Prime Minister's concerned.
嗯 你可以告诉他我的特工们正在地毯式搜索
Well, you can tell him my operatives are pursuing every avenue.
你考虑过撤回特工吗？
Have you considered pulling out the agents?
能考虑的办法我都考虑过
I've considered every option.
毫无冒犯之意 但这听起来像是逃避问题
Forgive me, that sounds like an evasion.
毫无冒犯之意 但为什么要叫我过来？
Forgive me, but why am I here?
三个月之前 你弄丢了一个硬盘 里面几乎包含了所有
Three months ago, you lost the computer drive containing the identity.
北约组织国家安插在全球恐怖组织中
of almost every NATO agent embedded in.
做卧底的特工身份名单
terrorist organizations across the globe.
至少 在我们同盟国的眼中 这个硬盘根本不存在
A list which, in the eyes of our allies, never existed.
所以请你原谅 我认为你很清楚为什么叫你过来
So if you'll forgive me, I think you know why you're here.
我们要称之为「监管平民」吗？
Are we to call this "civilian oversight"?
不 我们要称之为「退休计划」
No, we're to call this "retirement planning."
国家对你和你这么多年的工作
Your country has only the highest respect for you.
表示极大的感激和敬意
and your many years of service.
等你现任期满以后
When your current posting is completed,
你会被授予十字勋章的最高荣誉
you'll be awarded GCMG with full honors.
恭喜
Congratulations.
你要炒了我
You're firing me.
不 夫人 我来这是为了在你两个后资源退休前
No, ma'am, I'm here to oversee the transition period.
监管整个过渡期的
leading to your voluntary retirement in two months' time.
你的接班人还没有定 所以我们想问一下你…
Your successor has yet to be appointed, so we'll be asking you…
我不是白痴 马洛利
I'm not an idiot, Mallory.
我知道我不可能永远在这个位置上
I know I can't do this job forever.
但让我留下一堆麻烦然后走人
but I'll be damned if I'm going to leave the department.
我是坚决不肯的
in worse shape than I found it.
M 你已经做的很好了
M, you've had a great run.
你应该光荣隐退
You should leave with dignity.
哦 去他的光荣 等一切弄妥了我自会走人
Oh, to hell with dignity. I'll leave when the job's done.
喂？
Yes?
现在？
Now?
夫人 来自Q组的警报 有人试图解译被偷的硬盘
Ma'am, alert from Q-Branch. Someone's trying to decrypt the stolen hard drive.
我们正在追踪加密讯号
We're tracing the encryption signal.
正在定位
Localizing now.
是国内发出的
Centering in the UK.
就在伦敦
London.
尽快赶回总部
Get us back to base as soon as possible.
是从军情六处发出的
It's coming from Ml6.
什么？
What?
数据包正在连接我们的网络
The data packet is linking to our network.
不对 它在我们的防火墙里面
Correction. This is behind our firewall.
我们应该关掉系统
We should shut down.
别关 跟踪它
No, track it.
我们要找出具体位置
We have to know where it's coming from.
去掉标头 追踪来源
Strip the headers. Trace the source.
他们是怎么侵入我们系统的？
How the hell did they get into our system?
正在显示追踪结果
Getting trace back now.
上面显示…
It appears…
上面显示是从您的电脑上发出的 夫人
It appears to be your computer, ma'am.
关掉
Shut it down.
这是什么？
What is this?
（想想你的罪行）
搞什么名堂！
For God's sake!
赶紧把路让出来！
Just get out of the way!
- 你们认不出这辆车吗？- 夫人
- Don't you recognize the car? - Madam.
哦…
Oh…
这里是CNN突发新闻报导
This is CNN Breaking News.
紧急调查人员仍在估算损伤程度
Emergency crews are still attempting to assess.
警方也在全力追查这起
the damage as investigators hunt for leads.
发生在伦敦市中心的
in what now appears to be a major.
重大恐怖袭击的原因
terrorist attack in the heart of London.
目前还没有人声明要对此次发生在伦敦特情局的
No-one has yet claimed responsibility for what sources are calling.
「网络恐怖袭击」 事件负责
a possible "cyber-terrorist assault" on the British Secret Service.
此次事件初步调查显示
Early reports from the scene indicate.
至少有六人死亡 多人受伤
at least six dead, many more injured,
爆炸发生后几分钟后 伤者就被
with victims being evacuated to local hospitals.
送往了当地医院救治
within minutes of the explosion.
夫人 该走了
It's time to go, ma'am.
我会找出凶手的
I'm going to find whoever did this.
你一直都在哪？
Where the hell have you been?
在享受死亡
Enjoying death.
007回来复命
007 reporting for duty.
你干嘛不先打个电话？
Why didn't you call?
你没收到明信片吗？
You didn't get the postcard?
你也应该找时间试试 丢开一切
You should try it some time. Get away from it all.
真的能让你变得洞察一切
It really lends perspective.
那地方的酒都被你喝光了 对吧？
Ran out of drink where you were, did they?
你说什么来着？
What was it you said?
「快开枪」
"Take the bloody shot."
我只是根据形势做出了判断
I made a judgment call.
你应该相信我能完成任务
You should have trusted me to finish the job.
这可能会让你
It was the possibility of losing you.
或者其他特工命丧黄泉
or the certainty of losing all those other agents.
你知道 我只能做一个选择
I made the only decision I could and you know it.
我觉得是你没勇气
I think you lost your nerve.
你还指望什么 我给你道个歉？
What do you expect, a bloody apology?
你知道这游戏的规则
You know the rules of the game.
你已经玩了很久了
You've been playing it long enough.
我们都是如此
We both have.
或许太久了
Maybe too long.
这话对你自己说吧
Speak for yourself.
罗森没救活是吗？
Ronson didn't make it, did he?
是
No.
那么就这样了
So this is it.
我们全玩儿完了
We're both played out.
嗯 如果你这样认为 干嘛还回来？
Well, if you believe that, why did you come back?
问得好
Good question.
因为我们被袭击了
Because we're under attack.
你也知道我们需要你
And you know we need you.
所以我回来了
Well, I'm here.
你必须经过审查 然后判定是否合适参与任务
You'll have to be debriefed and declared fit for active service.
除非你通过测试 否则别想回来继续干
You can only return to duty when you've passed the tests,
所以认真一点
so take them seriously.
或许应该先洗个澡
And a shower might be in order.
我回家换个衣服
I'll go home and change.
哦 我们把你的公寓卖了 你的东西都放储藏室了
Oh, we've sold your flat, put your things into storage.
这是单身特工死后的标准处理程序
Standard procedure on the death of an unmarried employee.
你又没任何亲戚
with no next of kin.
你真的应该先打电话的
You should have called.
那我找个酒店
I'll find a hotel.
随便 总之你肯定不能住在这
Well, you're bloody well not sleeping here.
袭击者黑进了环境控制系统
The assailant hacked into the environmental control system,
锁了安全协议
locked out the safety protocols.
然后打开了燃气 能完成这些事按理说应该是不可能的
and turned on the gas, all of which should have been impossible.
然后他们黑进了她的档案
On top of that, they hacked into her files.
他们看了她的行程 知道她那时不在总部
They knew her appointments, knew she'd be out of the building.
他们的目标不是她
They weren't targeting her.
他们想让她目睹着一切
They wanted her to see it.
我们在哪 坦纳？
Where are we, Tanner?
新家
New digs.
原来的办公室对外宣称是「战略要害」
The old building was declared "strategically vulnerable".
这只是一种委婉的表达方式
That's putting it mildly.
他能够轻易侵入英国最安全的电脑系统
He was able to breach the most secure computer system in Britain.
所以我们现在处于战备状态
So we're on war footing now.
这里曾是丘吉尔时代地堡的一部分
This was part of Churchill's bunker.
我们还在探索这些历史
We're still discovering tunnels.
可以追溯到18世纪的隧道
dating back to the 18th Century.
要是没有老鼠 这环境还不错
Quite fascinating, if it wasn't for the rats.
我什么时候见M？
When do I see M?
如果你运气好的话明天就能见到M和马洛利
Tomorrow you'll see M and Mallory, too, if you're lucky.
马洛利是谁？
Who's Mallory?
情报安全委员会的新任主席
The new Chairman of the Intelligence and Security Committee.
是个魅力十足的男人 我觉得你和他
Charming man. I think you and he.
一定能合得来的
are really going to hit it off.
欢迎来到新军情六处
Welcome to the new MI6.
我们尝试追踪那条电脑信息的来源
We've attempted to trace the computer message, but.
但是发现数据经过了不对称加密计算
it was sent by an asymmetrical security algorithm,
通过一千多台不同的服务器
which bounced the signal all over the globe.
向全球反射信号
through over a thousand different servers.
而现在他们已经获取了M的密码
And now that they've accessed M's codes,
破解这份名单只是时间问题了
it's only a matter of time before they're able to decrypt the list.
Q组分析了图片 但到目前为止没有任何收获
Q-Branch have been analyzing the picture but so far nothing.
第一感觉很有可能是她过去的一位老友
The general feeling is it's probably someone from her past.
也许是她在香港执行任务那段时期认识的
Perhaps when she was running things in Hong Kong.
她对此毫无头绪
She's no idea what it all means.
这些你都信吗？
You believe that?
事实是 我们还没有窃取名单的人的线索
The truth is, we don't have a clue who took the list.
或者是他们打算拿来做什么
or what they plan to do with it.
我们完全可以随后再讨论这些问题
We can always do this later.
那就之后再说吧
You know what? Let's.
现在我们先做一些简单的词汇关联测试
I'd like to start with some simple word associations.
你只需告诉我出现在你脑海里的第一个词语
Just tell me the first word that pops into your head.
例如 我会说「一天」 你就说…
For example, I might say "Day" and you might say…
虚度
Wasted.
好的
All right.
枪械
Gun.
- 射击 - 特工
- Shot. - Agent.
奸细
Provocateur.
女人
Woman.
女奸细
Provocatrix.
心脏
Heart.
目标
Target.
鸟
Bird.
天空
Sky.
M夫人
M.
贱人
Bitch.
阳光
Sunlight.
游泳
Swim.
- 月光 - 舞蹈
- Moonlight. - Dance.
谋杀
Murder.
工作
Employment.
- 国家 - 英国
- Country. - England.
坠天庄园
Skyfall.
结束
Done.
好了 进行得还算顺利
Well, this is going well.
分析下这些东西
Get these analyzed.
结果只给她一个人看
For her eyes only.
她准备好见你了
She's ready for you.
很抱歉 我们之前见过吗？
I'm sorry, have we met before?
我才是那个该说「抱歉」的人
I'm the one who should say "sorry".
只弄断了我4根肋骨
It was only four ribs.
还有一些不太重要的器官
Some of the less vital organs.
没伤到重要部位
Nothing major.
在伊斯坦布尔的时候够刺激吗？
Not enough excitement in Istanbul?
我已经重新分配工作了
I've been reassigned.
暂时停止了现场任务
Temporary suspension from field work.
- 真的吗？- 没错
- Really? - Mmm.
都是因为我射杀了007
Something to do with killing 007.
好吧 你那一枪打得很准
Well, you gave it your best shot.
那根本不是我的最好水平
That was hardly my best shot.
要是用了最好水平 不知道我还能不能活下来
I'm not sure I could survive your best.
我想你不会有机会再试试了
I doubt you'll get the chance.
好吧 帮我个忙 可以吗？如果他们还让你出去执行任务的话
Well, do me a favor, will you? If they do ever let you back out there,
先通知下我
warn me first.
我现在在过渡期协助加雷斯·马洛利
I'm assisting Gareth Mallory in the transition,
然后我就会继续执行现场任务了
and then I'll be back in the field.
这就是你想要的？
That's what you want?
是的 当然了
Yes, of course.
这工作不是所有人都能做的
It's not for everyone.
007 这边请
Ah, 007. It's this way.
为你说句话 移动的目标射击难度更大
In your defense, a moving target is much harder to hit.
那你最好别停下脚步
Then you better keep moving.
整间办公室都烧光了
The whole office goes up in smoke.
那个该死的磁盘却没事
and that bloody thing survives.
很感谢你对原大楼内部装修的见解 007
Your interior decorating tips have always been appreciated, 007.
007 这位是加雷斯·马洛利
007, Gareth Mallory.
我希望我没错过什么
I hope I haven't missed anything.
首相在这场危机中还真是气定神闲
The PM does prattle on in a crisis.
你好 邦德
Bond.
你好 马洛利
Mallory.
我刚刚审阅了邦德的测试报告
I've just been reviewing Bond's tests.
看起来你通过了… 不过勉勉强强
It seems you've passed… by the skin of your teeth.
你现在复役了
You're back on active service.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
谢谢
Thank you.
我…
I'll, um…
还是出去等着吧
I'll be outside.
我只想问你一个问题
I only have one question.
你为什么又回来了？
Why not stay dead?
这是你隐退的绝佳机会 去一个宁静的地方安享晚年
You have the perfect way out. Go and live quietly somewhere.
不是所有的特工能这么彻底地离开这里
Not many field agents get to leave this cleanly.
你参与过很多现场任务吗？
Do you get out in the field much?
不做现场特工 并不意味着我不懂形势
You don't need to be an operative to see the obvious.
这是年轻人的行当
It's a young man's game.
听着 你受过重伤
Look, you've been seriously injured.
身手变笨拙了也不必觉得遗憾
There's no shame in saying you've lost a step.
唯一的遗憾就是承认得太晚
The only shame would be not admitting it until it's too late.
需不需要我 全凭你说了算
Hire me or fire me. It's entirely up to you.
如果他认为准备好了 那就没有问题
If he says he's ready, he's ready.
也许你看不出来 或许你根本不想看出来
Perhaps you can't see it, or maybe you won't.
你到底在暗示什么？
What exactly are you implying?
你对他太仁慈了
You're sentimental about him.
只要我还是这个部门的负责人 要什么人就是我说了算
As long as I'm head of this department, I'll choose my own operatives.
说的也是
Fair enough.
祝你好运 007
Good luck, 007.
别太骄傲
Don't cock it up.
我们分析了那些弹片
We've analyzed the shrapnel fragments.
你很走运 当时不是被直接命中
You're lucky it wasn't a direct hit.
否则就会把你切成两半
or it would have cut you in half.
这是一枚贫铀弹 军事级别
It's a depleted uranium shell. Military grade.
很难获取到 价格十分昂贵
Hard to get, extremely expensive,
并且是受限制使用的
and only used by a select few.
有认识的吗？
Recognize anyone?
是他
Him.
好的 这人叫帕特里斯
Okay. Name's Patrice.
他是个幽灵 没有固定住所或国籍资料
He's a ghost. No known residence or country of origin.
那我们怎样才能找到他？
So how do we find him?
幸运的是 我们在中情局还有人
Well, luckily, we still have one or two friends left in the CIA.
他们负责也门大使谋杀案 正在追查他
They're after him for the Yemeni ambassador's murder,
进展还算顺利
and they're getting close.
情报称 两天后他将会出现在上海
Intel is he's going to be in Shanghai.
可能是去工作
in two days time, probably on a job.
你现在出发 等候新的指示
You're to go there and await further instructions.
如果他出现了 就搞定他
If he turns up, he's yours.
查出他的雇主是谁 以及名单在谁手里
Find out who he works for and who has the list.
然后干掉他 为罗森报仇
Then terminate him, for Ronson.
乐意效劳
With pleasure.
还有什么要告诉我的吗？
Is there anything else you want to tell me?
没有
No.
向新的军需官报告你所需要的材料
Report to the new Quartermaster for your documentation.
他还没正式入职 但坦纳会安排
He hasn't set up shop yet, but Tanner will.
你们俩碰面 祝你好运
put you two together. Good luck.
谢谢
Thank you.
007 等等
007.
你准备好了吗？
You are ready for this?
是的 夫人
Yes, ma'am.
我不知道邦德通过了测试
I didn't know Bond passed the tests.
他没通过
He didn't.
这幅画总让我感觉到一丝忧伤
Always makes me feel a little melancholy.
一艘巨大的旧军舰以如此耻辱的方式被拖走报废
A grand old warship being ignominiously hauled away for scrap.
岁月催人老 你觉得呢？
The inevitability of time, don't you think?
你怎么看？
What do you see?
就是艘大军舰
A bloody big ship.
抱歉
Excuse me.
007 等等…
007…
我是你的新军需官
I'm your new Quartermaster.
你肯定在开玩笑
You must be joking.
怎么 就因为我没穿实验室外套吗？
Why, because I'm not wearing a lab coat?
因为你还太嫩了
Because you still have spots.
这和我的皮肤状况没什么关系
My complexion is hardly relevant.
好吧 但和你的能力有关
Well, your competence is.
年龄并不能保证工作效率
Age is no guarantee of efficiency.
年轻也无法保证一定能革新
And youth is no guarantee of innovation.
我敢打赌我穿着睡衣
I'll hazard I can do more damage.
用喝一杯格雷红茶的时间
on my laptop sitting in my pajamas.
在笔记本电脑上造成的伤害
before my first cup of Earl Grey.
比你执行任务一年制造的都多
than you can do in a year in the field.
哦 那你为什么还需要我呢？
Oh, so why do you need me?
有的时候还是需要有人冲锋陷阵
Every now and then a trigger has to be pulled.
也不一定
Or not pulled.
你的睡衣里有什么就很难说了
It's hard to know which in your pajamas.
你好 Q
Q.
你好 007
007.
这是去上海的机票
Ticket to Shanghai.
里面还有相关材料和护照
Documentation and passport.
谢谢
Thank you.
还有这个
And this.
沃尔特PPK/S9毫米手枪
Walther PPK/S 9mm short.
在手柄处有一个微型真皮传感器
There's a micro-dermal sensor in the grip.
里面录入了你的掌纹 所以只有你能使用这把抢
It's been coded to your palm print so only you can fire it.
减少了枪械走火误伤的概率 增加了个人表现的机会
Less of a random killing machine, more of a personal statement.
这个呢？
And this?
标准无线电通信设备
Standard issue radio transmitter.
激活它就能发送你所处位置的坐标
Activate it and it broadcasts your location.
就是救援信号
Distress signal.
就这些
And that's it.
一把手枪…
A gun…
还有一个无线电
and a radio.
礼物有点寒酸 对吧？
Not exactly Christmas, is it?
你想要一支爆破钢笔吗？
Were you expecting an exploding pen?
我们已经不研制那东西了
We don't really go in for that anymore.
祝你任务好运
Good luck out there in the field.
还有 请把这些设备完好地带回来
And please return the equipment in one piece.
勇敢新世界啊
Brave new world.
（上海）
（埃瓦航空226号航班 晚上9点到达）
名单在谁手里？
Who's got the list?
告诉我！你为谁卖命？
Tell me! Who are you working for?
坦纳… 他公布了前五个特工的姓名
Tanner… he's posted the first five names.
身份已经暴露了 他们现在有危险 让他们快撤离
Their cover's blown. They're in danger. Get them out now.
（想想你的罪行）
客房服务
Room service.
我没有点任何东西 更没有点你
I didn't order anything. Not even you.
我得到了一些新的情报
I've got some new information.
让你来传递情报是不是有点大材小用？
Aren't you a little overqualified to be delivering messages?
这也是学习曲线的一部分
It's all part of the learning curve.
而且Q很怕坐飞机
And Q's afraid of flying.
他当然怕了
Of course he is.
不管是谁窃取了名单 现在内容都已经破解了
So whoever stole the list has already decrypted it.
他们把名单的前五个姓名公布在网上了
They posted the first five names on the web.
嗯 早就说过这只是时间问题
Well, it was only a matter of time.
好吧 这仅仅是个开始
Well, that's just the start.
他们将每周公布五个新的名字
They're posting five more next week, and the week after.
这是在玩一场虐待狂游戏
It's some kind of sadistic game.
割喉剃刀
Cut-throat razor.
还是这么传统
How very traditional.
我喜欢用传统的方式做一些事情
Well, I like to do some things the old-fashioned way.
有时候传统的是最好的
Sometimes the old ways are the best.
你又要把命交到我手上了吗？
Are you putting your life in my hands again?
M已经…
M's…
向我简单介绍了一下那份名单
already briefed me on the list.
你来这儿真正的目的
Raising the tantalizing question.
就很令我好奇了
of what you're really doing here.
我的官方指令是来…
My official directive was to help…
「尽我所能」地帮助你
"in any way I can."
比如为马洛利监视我
Like spying for Mallory.
要知道 马洛利不像你想象的那么坏
You know, Mallory's not as bad as you think.
他是一个官僚主义
He's a bureaucrat.
你该好好做做功课了
You should do your homework.
加雷斯·马洛利曾是一个陆军上校…
Gareth Mallory was a Lieutenant Colonel…
北爱尔兰 赫里福德军团的陆军上校
Lieutenant Colonel in Northern Ireland, Hereford Regiment.
在爱尔兰共和军待过三个月
Spent three months at the hands of the IRA.
那么可以用大智若愚来形容他了
So there's more to him than meets the eye.
这个待议
We'll see.
别动
Keep still.
这下很难刮哦
This is the tricky part.
这样好多了
Now that's better.
你有点像以前那样了
You look the part now.
- 嗯？- 嗯
- Mm-hmm? - Mmm.
哪点像啊？
And what part's that?
人老大不小了
Old dog,
花招还是那么多
new tricks.
晚上好
Good evening.
好啊
Evening.
别碰你的耳朵
Don't touch your ear.
发现三个出口
I've got three exits,
很多监控盲点
lots of blind spots.
我处理好了
I've got them covered.
你穿这礼服美极了
You look beautiful in that dress.
你打扮得也不错嘛
You don't scrub up so bad yourself.
多双手 你就能神奇地做到很多事
It's amazing what one can do with an extra pair of hands.
你说呢
You're telling me.
你赌博吗？
Do you gamble?
我有时候小赌一把
I like a little flutter now and then.
谁不喜欢投机取巧呢？
Who doesn't like to take chances?
晚上好 先生 请问需要点什么？
Good evening, sir. How may I help you?
请帮我把这个兑现
I'd like to cash this in, please.
请等一下 先生
One moment, sir.
祝您今晚好运 先生
Good fortune tonight, sir.
希望如此
Let's hope so.
店家附赠的
With compliments of the house.
谢谢
Thank you.
你现在总能给我买杯酒了吧
Now you can afford to buy me a drink.
再多请一杯也没问题
Maybe I'll even stretch to two.
我猜这箱子里有四百万欧元
I'm guessing I've got four million euros in here.
不错啊 我还蛮喜欢这游戏的
Not bad. I like this game.
那要不我们换个玩玩？
Why don't we play another?
我不赌博
I don't gamble.
我生来运气就不好
I'm not very lucky.
看来跟我们在上海的朋友一样
A little like our friend in Shanghai.
我一直在等来兑现筹码的人
I've been waiting to see who would redeem the chip.
你就这么大摇大摆地闯进我们的布局
You made such a bold entrance into our little drama.
是我想的太复杂了吗？
Did I over-complicate the plot?
谁不喜欢偶尔来一段小插曲啊 先生…
Who doesn't appreciate the occasional twist, Mr…
邦德
Bond.
我叫詹姆斯·邦德
James Bond.
我叫赛菲林
Severine.
邦德先生 那我们要不边喝酒边聊聊你的下步计划？
So, Mr. Bond, shall we discuss your next performance over that drink?
正合我意
I'd like that.
你朋友也要跟过来吗？
Will your friends be joining us?
恐怕这个是难免的了
That, I'm afraid, is inevitable.
她长得还不错
She's pretty.
别说了
Now, now.
如果你好这口的话
If you like that sort of thing.
有好戏我会通知你的
I'll keep you posted.
好极了
Perfect.
介意我问一个生意上的问题吗？
Would you mind if I asked you a business question?
那要看什么问题了
Depends on the question.
是跟生死有关的事情
It has to do with death.
这事情你也应该很了解才是
A subject in which you're well-versed.
你怎么知道的呢？
And how would you know that?
穿露背装 大腿上绑着伯莱塔70枪的
Only a certain kind of woman wears a backless dress.
也就只有一种女人
with a Beretta 70 strapped to her thigh.
就是对穿礼服还揣着沃尔特收枪的帅气男人
One can never be too careful when.
小心再小心的那种女人
handsome men in tuxedos carry Walthers.
我猜你杀了帕特里斯 是没猜错咯？
I am correct in assuming you killed Patrice?
没错
Yes.
我能问原因吗？
Might I ask why?
我想见见你的老板
I want to meet your employer.
许愿的时候 要小心一点
Be careful what you wish for.
你很害怕
You're scared.
谢谢你的酒啦
Thank you for the drink,
邦德先生
Mr. Bond.
你演戏演得不错
You put on a good show.
不过从我们坐下之后 你就不停地
But ever since we sat down, you haven't stopped.
看你的保镖
looking at your bodyguards.
配三个保镖 稍微多了点吧
Three of them is a bit excessive.
他们不是在保护你 是在监控你吧
They're controlling you. They're not protecting you.
你腕上的纹身是澳门性交易组织的
The tattoo on your wrist is Macau sex trade.
你属于其中一家 会是哪家呢？12号？还是13号？
You belonged to one of the houses. What were you? 12? 13?
我猜 他是你赎身的希望
I'm guessing he was your way out.
也许你觉得 你是爱上他了
Perhaps you thought you were in love.
但那已经是很早之前的事情了
But that was a long time ago.
你不知道别瞎说
You know nothing about it.
我知道女人害怕还要假装镇定是什么样子
I know when a woman is afraid and pretending not to be.
恐惧 你懂多少？
How much do you know about fear?
完全明白
All there is.
这个不一样
Not like this.
他不一样
Not like him.
我能帮你
I can help you.
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
至少让我试试
Let me try.
怎么试？
How?
带我去见他
Bring me to him.
你能杀了他吗？
Can you kill him?
能
Yes.
真的吗？
Will you?
人总要死的
Someone usually dies.
也许你真的可以
Perhaps you can.
等我走了 他们就打算动手杀你
When I leave, they're going to kill you.
如果你活着出去 我在北港的基梅拉
If you survive, I'm on the Chimera. North harbor.
七号码头
Berth seven.
我们一小时后起航
We cast off in an hour.
很高兴见到你 邦德先生
Very nice to have met you, Mr. Bond.
祝你好运
Good luck.
自求多福吧
Good luck with that.
谢谢
Thank you.
全压在红色上吧
Put it all on red.
生不带来 死不带去
It's the circle of life.
请进！
Yes!
该起航了
It's time to cast off.
好吧
All right.
你不带伯莱塔的样子更迷人
I like you better without your Beretta.
没有它 我浑身不自在
I feel naked without it.
晚上好
Good evening.
关于国防部的争论今天进一步扩大
The controversy surrounding the Ministry of Defence has escalated today.
源于侯赛因刺杀事件的图像不断曝光
as images of the Husein assassination continue to circulate.
本台提醒大家 这些图片可能会
We should warn you, some viewers.
引起部分人身体不适
might find these images disturbing.
侯赛因上校是一名在中东地区卧底的军情六处探员
Captain Husein, an MI6 operative embedded in the Middle East,
也是五名被曝光的
was one of the five agents exposed.
探员之一 此事件也成为
in what is now being considered.
现代英国史上最严重的内部安全漏洞
the greatest internal security breach in modern British history.
首相继续呼吁公众支持军情六处
The Prime Minister continues to express public support for MI6…
同时反对者已经表明…
while the opposition has taken the position…
已经表明 我们就是一群过时的老白痴
Has taken the position we're a bunch of antiquated bloody idiots.
还愚蠢地打着一无所知还希望渺茫的仗
fighting a war we don't understand and can't possibly win.
听着 我手下已经有三名探员殉职了
Look, three of my agents are dead already.
别用政治来搪塞我
Don't embroil me in politics now.
首相下令进行听证 你到时必须参加
The Prime Minister's ordered an inquiry. You'll have to appear.
大白天站在人群当中？看看现在谁好糊弄了？
Oh, standing in the stocks at midday? Who's antiquated now?
天啊 你自己听听自己在说什么 我们是民主社会
For Christ's sake, listen to yourself. We're a democracy,
要对我们保护的人负责
accountable to the people we're trying to defend.
我们没法暗箱操作了 事情已经败露
We can't keep working in the shadows. There are no more shadows.
你还没开窍 是吧？
You don't get this, do you?
不管幕后主脑是谁 不管这一切是谁做的 他对我们了如指掌
Whoever's behind this, whoever's doing it, he knows us.
他是我们的一员 他和邦德同出一处
He's one of us. He comes from the same place as Bond.
就来自你说不存在的那个地方
The place you say doesn't exist.
阴暗的地方
The shadows.
现在为时不晚 我们现在还能掉头
It's not too late. We could turn back now.
我可不这么认为
I wouldn't be so sure.
他们一夜间就废弃了这小岛
They abandoned it almost overnight.
他让他们以为这座岛上有化学试剂泄漏
He made them think there was a leak at the chemical plant.
你会惊讶 小小的一台电脑就能引起这么大的恐慌
It's amazing the panic you can cause with a single computer.
他想要这座岛 就伸手拿了
He wanted the island, so he took it.
他总能要什么 就得到什么吗？
Does he always get what he wants?
超乎你的想象
More than you know.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你好 詹姆斯 欢迎欢迎
Hello, James. Welcome.
你喜欢这岛吗？
Do you like the island?
我外婆就有座小岛
My grandmother had an island.
没什么好炫耀的 那个岛一个小时就能走遍
Nothing to boast of. You could walk around it in an hour.
但那地方对我们来说 还是和天堂一般
But still, it was, it was a paradise for us.
某个夏天 我们去看外婆的时候
One summer, we went for a visit.
发现那地方已经被老鼠占据了
and discovered the place had been infested with rats!
它们乘着钓鱼的船到了岛上 靠吃椰子为生
They'd come on a fishing boat and gorged themselves on coconut.
你知道怎么把老鼠赶出小岛吗？
So how do you get rats off an island? Hmm?
我外婆演示给我看的
My grandmother showed me.
我们埋了一个油桶 上面系着木桶盖
We buried an oil drum and hinged the lid,
然后把椰子系在木桶盖上做诱饵
then wired coconut to the lid as bait.
老鼠来吃那个椰子 接着…
And the rats would come for the coconut and…
就自然而然掉进了木桶里面
they would fall into the drum.
过一个月 就能逮到所有的老鼠
And after a month, you have trapped all the rats.
那接下来怎么处理那木桶呢？
But what do you do then?
把木桶扔到海里？
Throw the drum into the ocean?
烧了木桶？不是
Burn it? No.
就把木桶放在那里
You just leave it.
然后老鼠会越来越饿
And they begin to get hungry.
一个接一个…
And one by one…
它们开始撕咬对方
they start eating each other.
直到剩下最后两个 就两只幸存了下来
until there are only two left. The two survivors.
然后怎样？杀了它们？不是
And then what? Do you kill them? No.
你只要放它们回归树林就行
You take them and release them into the trees.
但那时候 它们不再吃椰子了
But now they don't eat coconut anymore.
它们只吃老鼠
Now they only eat rat.
你改变了它们的天性
You have changed their nature.
两个幸存者
The two survivors,
她就是这么造就我们的
this is what she made us.
我做了自己的选择
I made my own choices.
你以为是自己选的
You think you did.
这就是她天才的地方
That's her genius.
H站 我说对了吗？在香港
Station H. Am I right? Hong Kong.
没错
Mm-hmm.
从86年待到97年
'86 to '97.
那时候 我是她的首选
Back then, I was her favorite.
我跟你说 你跟我简直没法比
And you're not nearly the agent I was, I can tell you that.
看看你自己 靠着药片酒精才勉强活着
Just look at you, barely held together by your pills and your drink.
别忘了我对国家那点可怜的热爱
Don't forget my pathetic love of country.
你还是对那老女人有着信仰
You're still clinging to your faith in that old woman.
- 她所做的只是欺骗你而已 - 她从来没骗过我
- When all she does is lie to you. - She never lied to me.
- 从来没有？- 没有
- No? - No.
你枪法测试最后成绩如何？
What did you score in your marksmanship evaluation?
70分
70.
其实只有40分
40.
她跟你说 心理医师准许你复职上任吗？
Did she tell you the psychologist cleared you for duty?
- 是的 - 大错特错
- Yes. - No. No.
药物检测 不合格 体能测试 不合格
Medical evaluation, fail. Physical evaluation, failed.
心理检测
Psychological evaluation,
「依赖酒精和成瘾物」
"Alcohol and substance addiction indicated."
「由于未痊愈的童年心理创伤
"Pathological rejection of authority.
对权威有病态的排斥心理「
based on unresolved childhood trauma."
「测试对象不允许执行任务
"Subject is not approved for field duty.
并建议立即停职相关工作「
and immediate suspension from service advised."
如果这不是背叛 那又是什么？
What is this if not betrayal?
明知你还没准备好 有可能会牺牲 但她还是派你来调查我
She sent you after me knowing you're not ready, knowing you'll likely die.
妈咪做人不厚道！
Mommy was very bad!
对吧？
Hmm?
哦
Ooh.
看她都对你做了什么？
See what she's done to you?
她至少没把我绑在椅子上
Well, she never tied me to a chair.
那是她的损失
Her loss.
你确定这是和M有关系吗？
Are you sure this is about M?
这和她有关
It's about her.
和你和我更有关
And you, and me.
我们就是剩下的那两只老鼠
You see, we are the last two rats.
我们可以自相残杀…
We can either eat each other…
如何？
hmm?
或者对其他人下手
Or eat everyone else.
你在拼命回忆以前做过的训练
How you're trying to remember your training now.
这种情形该如何解决？
What's the regulation to cover this?
凡事都有第一次的 不是吗？
Well, first time for everything. Yes?
为什么你会觉得我是第一次呢？
What makes you think this is my first time?
哦 邦德先生！
Oh, Mr. Bond!
那些体能训练… 愚蠢 太愚蠢了
All that physical stuff… so dull, so dull.
追捕间谍…
Chasing spies…
老掉牙了！
so old-fashioned!
你的膝盖肯定疼死了吧
Your knees must be killing you.
英格兰
England.
女王！军情六处！
The Empire! MI6!
你也是活着废墟里的
You're living in a ruin as well,
你只是不知道而已
you just don't know it yet.
至少在这里 没有老女人冲你发号施令 也没有…
At least here there are no old ladies giving orders and no little…
哔哔！
bip!
没那么多Q组的小玩意
Gadgets from those fools in Q-Branch.
要是你想的话 你可以自己选择机密任务 就像我一样
If you wanted, you could pick your own secret missions. As I do.
开口说就行 直接说就行了
Name it. Name it.
通过控制股票来动摇一个国际大集团
Destabilize a multinational by manipulating stocks…
哔哔 就这么简单
Bip. Easy.
中断喀布尔间谍卫星的通信…
Interrupt transmissions from a spy satellite over Kabul…
搞定
Done.
操纵乌干达的选举 让出价最高者获胜
Rig an election in Uganda. All to the highest bidder.
或是在伦敦引起瓦斯爆炸
Or a gas explosion in London.
选个地方 点确定就可以了
Just point and click.
只能说 萝卜青菜各有所爱
Well, everybody needs a hobby.
那你想要什么？
So what's yours?
重新崛起
Resurrection.
给你看点东西
Let me show you something.
景致不错 对吧？
Tells a story, doesn't it?
他们跑得太匆忙了
They left the island so quickly,
来不及考虑需要带什么
they couldn't decide what to take,
需要舍弃什么 什么才是最重要的
what to leave, what was important.
这片废墟无时无刻地提醒我 做事要抓重点
And seeing this every day reminds me to focus on the essentials.
我从来… 从来不做无关紧要的事情
There's nothing… nothing superfluous in my life.
在我看来多余的东西 都要被消灭掉
When a thing is redundant, it is eliminated.
50年陈酿麦卡伦
50-year-old Macallan.
我知道这是你的最爱
A particular favorite of yours, I understand.
那么 为什么而干杯呢？
So, what's the toast?
「为了我们心爱的女人」？
"To the women we love?"
亲爱的
Darling.
亲爱的 你的情人都在这儿
Darling, your lovers are here.
不 不 不
No, no, no, no.
给我站直了 别动
Stand up straight. Keep still.
不管做什么 头别晃哦
And whatever you do, don't lose your head.
保持住…
Don't lose…
头别动
your head.
头别乱动
Don't lose your head.
是时候重新测验你的枪技了
Time to redeem your marksmanship scores.
拭目以待
Let's see.
我们谁先打碎她头上的杯子呢？
Who can be the first to knock the glass from her head?
为了体现公平 我让你先来
And just to be sporting, I'll let you go first.
看看你们谁先死
Let's see who ends up on top.
我真不敢相信
Oh, I can't believe it.
真不相信！你那天难道真的死了？
I can't believe it! Did you really die that day?
难道007已经沦落到不敢开枪了？
Is there any, any of the old 007 left?
到我了
My turn.
我赢了 你怎么看？
I win. What do you say to that?
多好的威士忌 都浪费了
It's a waste of good Scotch.
那么你要做什么？把我带回去？就凭你一个人？
What are you going to do now? Take me back to her? All on your own?
谁说我是一个人的？
Who says I'm on my own?
Q组的最新设备
It's the latest thing from Q-Branch.
无线电通信设备
It's called a radio.
好吧 该打声招呼了
All right, time to say hello.
你比我印象中瘦多了！
You're smaller than I remember!
可我完全不记得你了
Whereas I barely remember you at all.
那可怪了 对我来说 就像昨日重现一样
Strange. For me, it feels just like yesterday.
你是不是很惊讶？
Are you surprised?
那倒不是 但你总是特工中最狡猾的一个
Not particularly. But then you always were a slippery one.
也许这就是为什么你那么喜欢我
Maybe that's why you liked me so much.
别自吹自擂了
You flatter yourself.
一点都没后悔
No remorse.
正如我所预料的一样
Just as I had imagined.
悔恨是不专业的表现
Regret is unprofessional.
「悔恨是不专业的表现」
"Regret is unprofessional."
他们把我关在不见天日的囚室里 折磨我
They kept me for five months in a room with no air. They tortured me.
我一直没有招供你的机密 我保护了你
And I protected your secrets. I protected you.
但他们一直折磨我 折磨我
But they made me suffer. And suffer.
折磨我
And suffer.
直到我意识到…
Until I realized…
是你背叛了我
it was you who betrayed me.
你背叛了我
You betrayed me.
所以我只剩一个选择了
So, I had only one thing left.
在我左边臼齿下藏的那颗毒药胶囊
My cyanide capsule in my back left molar.
你还记得 对吧？
You remember, right?
所以 我咬断牙齿…
So I broke the tooth and…
吃下了那颗胶囊
bit into the capsule.
然后…
And it…
我就感觉全身都在燃烧
it burned all my insides.
但我没死
But I didn't die.
生命就像狗皮膏药 粘着不走
Life clung to me like a disease.
然后…
And then…
我意识到我为什么活下来了
I understood why I had survived.
我想再最后和你对视一次
I needed to look in your eyes one last time.
我希望对你来说是值得的
Well, I hope it was worth it.
西法先生 你将被送去贝尔马什监狱
Mr. Silva, you're going to be transferred to Belmarsh Prison.
你将在那被关押直到
where you'll be remanded in custody.
皇家检察院
until the Crown Prosecution Service.
认为你可以受审…
deem you fit to stand trial for…
说我的名字 说啊
Say my name. Say it.
我的真名
My real name.
我知道你记得的
I know you remember it.
你的名字是刻在你所袭击
Your name is on the memorial wall.
总部纪念墙上
of the very building you attacked.
我将把你的名字剔除
I will have it struck off.
很快你就会失去你的过去和未来
Soon your past will be as nonexistent as your future.
我也不会再见到你
I'll never see you again.
你知道那东西把我害成什么样了吗？
Do you know what it does to you?
那个氰化氢胶囊？
Hydrogen cyanide?
看看你的成果吧
Look upon your work.
妈妈
Mother.
一旦破解他电脑里的信息就通知我
Let me know what you recover from his computer.
他有没有把名单给其他人？如果有 给谁了？赶快解决这件事
Has he transmitted the lists? If so, to whom? I want this resolved.
知道了 夫人
Yes, ma'am.
他叫迪亚果·罗德里格斯
His name is Tiago Rodriguez.
曾经是个很出色的特工
He was a brilliant agent.
但是他曾经越职违规 黑入中国的电脑系统
But he started operating beyond his brief, hacking the Chinese.
他们提出移交 目标是那个特工 所以我放弃他了
The handover was coming up and they were onto him, so I gave him up.
我们换回了六个特工安全回归
I got six agents in return and a peaceful transition.
我们该走了 夫人 听证会将在30分钟后开始
We should go, ma'am. Board of Inquiry begins in 30 minutes.
我要知道那电脑里的一切
I want to know what's on that computer.
面前的这台就是西法的电脑了
Now, looking at Silva's computer,
在我看来 他也还是有点才华的
it seems to me he's done a number of slightly unusual things.
他设计了一个安全破坏机制
He's established failsafe protocols to wipe the memory.
如果要查看某些文件 电脑将自动删除所有内存
if there's any attempt to access certain files.
世界上会这种编程的屈指可数
Only six people in the world could program safeguards like that.
当然不会那么简单 你能破解吗？
Of course there are. Can you get past them?
这种编程是我发明的
I invented them.
好了
Right, then.
我们看看你准备了什么大礼 西法先生
Let's see what you've got for us, Mr. Silva.
入侵成功
We're in.
长官 这个如何处理？
Sir, what do you make of this?
这是电脑的核心程式
It's his Omega site.
最难破译的部分
Most encrypted level he has.
看上去使用极其复杂的代码来隐藏其核心程序
Looks like obfuscated code to conceal its true purpose.
一种复杂化的加密手段
Security through obscurity.
先生们 女士们 请保持肃静
Ladies and gentlemen, if I might have order?
现在会议开始
I'd like to begin the proceedings.
我们今天聚首 是为了强调一个很严重的问题
We're gathered today to address important issues.
关系到国土未来安全的一个重大问题
concerning the future of our national security.
这是要去远足吗？
Going somewhere?
那么你认为自己在这段危机时刻对于军情六处的
So you believe your stewardship of Ml6 during the recent crisis.
管理是完全称职的吗？
has been up to scratch?
我觉得我们已经抓获主要嫌犯
Well, I believe we have apprehended the responsible party.
而且采取了一切必要措施
and are taking all necessary steps.
来保证机密信息不至于外泄
to ensure that the sensitive information is contained.
那么说 你们做得很好咯
So it's a job well done.
我们不否认之前的一些错误 但是…
I'm not saying it's gone perfectly, but…
你想你会原谅我没给你发国旗奖励你
You'll forgive me for not putting up the bunting.
我想你不会忽视那次
I find it rather difficult to overlook monumental.
系统入侵 从而导致特工丧生
security breaches and dead operatives.
而这一切都是因为你一个人的失职
for which you are almost single-handedly responsible.
他用了一个多态引擎来随时改变代码
He's using a polymorphic engine to mutate the code.
每当我想要入侵 代码便发生改变
whenever I try to gain access, it changes.
就像玩一个会反抗的魔方一样
It's like solving a Rubik's cube that's fighting back.
停下
Stop.
从那里试试
Go in on that.
白金汉
Granborough.
白金汉路 是一个都市线的老地铁站
Granborough Road. It's an old Tube station on the Metropolitan Line.
很多年没用过了
Been closed for years.
把这个当做密钥试试
Use that as a key.
出来了 是个地图！
Oh, look, it's a map!
是伦敦
It's London.
伦敦的地下通道
Subterranean London.
发生什么事情了？门怎么都打开了？
What's going on? Why are the doors open?
不
Oh, no.
谁能告诉我 他是怎么入侵到我们系统的？
Can someone tell me how the hell he got into our system?
该死
Oh, shit.
该死 该死
Oh, shit, shit, shit.
他黑了我们的系统
He hacked us.
不
Oh, no.
喂 Q
Q.
他不见了
He's gone.
我在隔离区下面的楼梯井
I'm in a stairwell below isolation.
能听到吗 Q？
Do you read me, Q?
我听到了 我正在找你呢
I can hear you. I'm looking for you.
收到 正在地图上定位
Got you. Tracking your location.
照直往前走
Just keep moving forward.
进入下一个安全门 在你右边
Enter the next service door on your right.
如果你过了门 你应该就到地铁隧道了
If you're through that door, you should be in the Tube.
我在隧道里
I'm in the Tube.
邦德 这不是一次简单的逃脱 是经过多年精心策划的
Bond, this isn't an escape. This was years in the planning.
是他故意让我们抓到他 故意让我们解析他的电脑的
He wanted us to capture him, he wanted us to access his computer.
这都是计划好的
It was all planned.
总部的爆炸 我们的紧急措施
Blowing up HQ. Knowing the emergency protocols.
他知道我们会撤离到这儿
Knowing we'd retreat down here.
这我都知道了 我担心的是他的下一步计划
I've got all that. It's what he's got planned next that worries me.
地铁站是最近的出口 你的左边有一个安全门
District Line is the closest. There's a service door on your left.
知道了
Got it.
打不开
It won't open.
可以的 使劲推就会开
It will. Put your back into it.
为什么你不下来自己试试呢？
Why don't you come down here and put your back into it?
不行 被堵住了
No, it's stuck.
好极了 有辆地铁过来了
Oh, good. There's a train coming.
惊心动魄啊
Hmm. That's vexing.
我进去了
I'm through.
早说了能开的
Told you.
我想已经触发地铁警报了 警察会赶过来
We alerted security. Police are on their way.
你现在在哪？
Where are you now?
天普地铁站
Temple Tube station.
还赶上了伦敦的上班潮
Along with half of London.
看到你了 在这儿
Oh, I see you. There you are.
我知道我在哪儿 Q 他呢？
I know where I am, Q. Where's he?
等我一下 我在找
Give us a second. I'm looking for him.
注意站台间缝隙
Mind the gap.
人太多了 我找不到他
There's too many people. I can't see him.
欢迎在上班高峰乘坐地铁
Welcome to rush hour on the Tube.
估计你没体会过人流高峰期的地铁
Not something you'd know much about.
注意站台间缝隙
Mind the gap.
车就要走了 我乘这趟车子吗？
The train's leaving. Do I get on the train?
别上车 我还不确定他上去了 等我一下
Don't get on. I'm not sure he's on it. Give us a minute.
我到底上不上车？
Do I get on the train?
邦德
Bond.
- 怎么了？- 快上车
- What? - Get on the train.
他想回家想疯了吧
He's keen to get home.
能否开下门？
Will you open the door, please?
开门
Open the door.
卫生安全部门的 你继续工作
Health and Safety. Carry on.
你在哪？
Where are you?
你猜呢 Q
Take a wild guess, Q.
他换装了 伪装成警察了
He's in disguise, dressed as a policeman.
当然
Of course he is.
他去哪儿了？去哪儿了？
Where's he going? Where's he going?
他朝M那边去了 告诉坦纳 让她赶紧离开
He's going for M. Tell Tanner. Get her out of there.
你忽视了 或是说故意无视那些铁证
You've overlooked, or chosen to ignore, hard evidence.
并且一贯地 固执地…
and consistently, almost obstinately…
西法逃走了 邦德正在追捕
Silva's escaped. Bond's in pursuit.
我们得立刻让你到安全的地方避难
We need to get you to a secure location immediately.
如果我现在转身走人 会被她骂死的
I'll be damned if I'm gonna show her my back.
我们让你走神了？
Are we straining your attention?
没有 首相 请您继续
No. Please, Minister, proceed.
借过
Excuse me.
走开！走开！
Move! Move!
好像你一直幻想着
It's as if you insist on pretending.
我们还处于谍战时代
we still live in a golden age of espionage.
说什么情报部门的信息才是最可靠的
where human intelligence was the only resource available.
我觉得这种老套的观念
Well, I find this rather old-fashioned belief.
体现出你根本无视…
demonstrates a reckless disregard for…
抱歉 首相 我不是有意打断你
Excuse me, Minister, I don't mean to interrupt,
但是为了听证的合理
but just for the sake of variety,
我们是否应该传唤目击者呢？
might we actually hear from the witness?
当然
Of course.
谢谢
Thank you.
下一击我可不会射偏了 西法先生
I won't miss next time, Mr. Silva.
不错啊 詹姆斯 受了伤准头还那么高
Not bad. Not bad, James, for a physical wreck.
谢了
Thank you.
你逮到我了
You caught me.
作为给你的奖励
Now, here's your prize.
我玩具店里的最新产品
The latest thing from my local toy store.
叫做无线电通信设备
It's called radio.
真精彩！
Whew!
我希望这个不是为我准备的
I do hope that wasn't for me.
当然不是
No.
这才是为你准备的
But that is.
主席 各位秘书长
Chairman. Ministers.
今天我多次听到
Today I've repeatedly heard how.
我的部门是多么的不值一提
irrelevant my department has become.
为什么我们还需要特工？为什么我们还需要这个组织？
Why do we need agents? The Double-O section?
这一切是不是已经过时了？
Isn't it all rather quaint?
我想说 我看到的与你们看到的是不同的世界
Well, I suppose I see a different world than you do.
我所见到的东西深深震撼了我
And the truth is that what I see frightens me.
我的恐惧是因为我们的敌人不再是我们熟知的那些
I'm frightened because our enemies are no longer known to us.
他们躲在黑暗里
They do not exist on a map.
他们不是任何的国家 而是个人
They're not nations. They are individuals.
看看周围 你怕的是谁？
Look around you. Who do you fear?
你能看到一张面孔？一件制服？一面旗帜？你什么都看不到
Can you see a face? A uniform? A flag? No.
这个世界如今越来越复杂
Our world is not more transparent now.
越来越难以捉摸
It's more opaque.
一切都躲在影子里
It's in the shadows.
这就是我们必须战斗的原因
That's where we must do battle.
所以 在决定解散我们之前 请你扪心自问
So, before you declare us irrelevant, ask yourselves,
你是否觉得安全？
How safe do you feel?
我还有一件事想说
I've just one more thing to say.
我的上一任丈夫非常热爱诗歌
My late husband was a great lover of poetry.
而且…
And, um…
虽然并非我本意 但还是受到了些许熏陶
I suppose some of it sunk in, despite my best intentions.
今天的一切又让我想起了这首丁尼生的诗：
And here today I remember this, I think from Tennyson.
如今我们已力衰
We are not now that strength,
全无往昔风采
which in old days moved earth and heaven.
但我们仍然是自己
That which we are, we are.
有英雄的情怀与雄心
One equal temper of heroic hearts,
虽因时间和命运
made weak by time.
日益衰减
and fate,
但意志依然坚定
but strong in will.
去奋斗 去追求
To strive, to seek,
去找寻
to find.
永不屈服
and not to yield.
走 走 走 快走！
Go, go, go, go!
快走！
Move!
别磨蹭！走！快走！
Move! Go! Move!
007 你在干什么？你是要绑架我吗？
007, what the hell are we doing? Are you kidnapping me?
看起来的确是这样
That would be one way of looking at it.
太多人因为我而死了
Too many people are dying because of me.
如果他想要你的命 他肯定会来找你的
If he wants you, he'll have to come and get you.
我们从开始就比西法慢一步
We've been one step behind Silva from the start.
是时候逆转乾坤 领先一步了
It's time to get out in front, change the game.
那我就是那个诱饵？
And I'm to be the bait?
是的 但是只有我们 没有别人
All right. But just us. No one else.
Q？我需要帮助
Q? I need help.
我在跟踪你们的车 你们要去哪儿？
I'm tracking the car. Where are you going?
我和M在一起 我们现在要消失
I've got M. We're about to disappear.
什么？
What?
我需要你把我们的痕迹统统清除
I need you to lay a trail of breadcrumbs impossible to follow.
但要留下只有西法能跟踪到的 我想你做得到对吗？
for anyone except Silva. Think you can do it?
我想这事不会被批准的
I'm guessing this isn't strictly official.
根本不可能
Not even remotely.
看来这会毁了我的大好仕途
So much for my promising career in espionage.
如果你的好主意就是躲在这儿 我可不乐意
I'm not hiding in there, if that's your brilliant plan.
我们要换辆车
We're changing vehicles.
不能用军情六处的车 因为车上有跟踪器
Trouble with company cars is they have trackers.
我想这车真是太掩人耳目了
Oh, and I suppose that's completely inconspicuous.
快上车
Get in.
车没那么舒服吧 是吗？
It's not very comfortable, is it?
你想一路抱怨过去吗？
Are you gonna complain the whole way?
那把我弹射出去啊 我不在乎
Oh, go on then, eject me. See if I care.
我们这是去哪儿？
Where are we going?
去一切开始的地方
Back in time.
去一个对我们有利的地方
Somewhere we'll have the advantage.
这真是很难掌握
It's a fine line.
留的线索太少了怕他找不到
Make the breadcrumb too small and he might miss it.
留的太多了又怕西法起疑心
Too big and Silva will smell a rat.
但你觉得西法会注意到你留的线索吗？
But do you think even Silva will be able to spot that?
他是唯一能懂的人
He's the only one who could.
长官
Sir.
是的
Oh.
你们在干嘛？
What are you doing?
我们只是在… 监控
We're just… monitoring.
制造一个假信号让西法跟踪
Creating a false tracking signal for Silva to follow.
- 这个 长官… - 不是
- Well, sir, um… - Well, no.
这想法很好 把他孤立开来
Excellent thinking. Get him isolated.
让他上A9公路 这条路没有岔口
Send him on the A9. It's the direct route.
你可以更准确地监视到他的动向
You can monitor his progress more accurately.
还能用公路探头监视
and confirm it with the traffic cameras.
如果被首相发现了呢？
But what if the PM finds out?
那我们都玩完了
Then we're all buggered.
继续吧
Carry on.
这里就是你长大的地方吗？
Is this where you grew up?
是的
Mm.
你父母在你多大的时候去世的？
How old were you when they died?
你知道答案的
You know the answer to that.
整件事你都知道
You know the whole story.
孤儿是最好的新兵人选
Orphans always make the best recruits.
暴风雨要来了
Storm's coming.
天啊
Christ.
就是这儿
Mm-hmm.
怪不得你从来不回来
No wonder you never came back.
詹姆斯
James.
詹姆斯·邦德
James Bond.
天啊
Good God.
你还活着？
Are you still alive?
很高兴再见到你
It's nice to see you, too.
M 这一位是金凯德
M, this is Kincade.
从我小时候就在这里看家护院
Gamekeeper here since I was a boy.
很高兴见到你 艾玛
Pleased to meet you, Emma.
你也是 金凯德先生
Mr. Kincade.
你回来晚了 他们已经把这里卖了
You're a tad late. They've sold the place,
他们以为你死了
when they thought you were dead.
看起来他们错了
It seems they were wrong.
你来这儿做什么？
What are you doing here?
有人在追杀我们
Some men are coming to kill us.
但我们会先杀了他们
But we're gonna kill them first.
那我们最好早作准备
Then we'd better get ready.
我们的武器库还在吗？
Do we still have a gun room?
啊
Ah.
他们把很多抢都卖给了从什么爱达荷州来的收藏家
They sold the lot to a collector from Idaho or some such place.
一星期之前都被运走了
They were shipped out weeks ago.
现在只剩下…
There's just…
你爸爸留下的老猎枪了
your father's old hunting rifle.
我们不忍心卖掉这把
We couldn't let that go.
就只有这些了
And this is what we've got.
好像还有些从采石场弄来的雷管
There might be a couple of sticks of dynamite from the quarry.
如果这些都没用的话
But if all else fails,
有时候老办法才是最好的
sometimes the old ways are the best.
那我们要对付的是谁？
So who is it we're supposed to be fighting?
不是「我们」 金凯德
No "we" in it, Kincade.
你不该被卷进来的
This is not your fight.
别想阻止我 你这臭小子
Try and stop me, you jumped-up little shit.
现在 记住我教你的 别往左偏
Now, remember what I taught you. Don't let it pull to the left.
我试试看
I'll do my best.
你说你是干什么工作的？
What did you say you did for a living?
艾玛！
Emma!
我给你带了点好东西
I brought you some things.
这里晚上很冷的
The nights get cold here.
谢谢你 金凯德先生
Thank you, Mr. Kincade.
这真是间漂亮的老房子
It's a beautiful old house.
她的确很漂亮
She is.
就像所有女士一样 她也有自己的秘密
And like all great ladies, she still has her secret ways.
让我带你参观一下
Let me show you this.
一个祭祀洞？
Priest's hole?
是的 工业革命的时候留下的
Yeah, from Reformation times.
隧道一直通向外面的沼泽
The tunnel leads under the moor.
如果你遇到危险 这里是最好的藏身之处
If you get in danger, this is the place to come.
那晚我告诉他双亲去世了 他在里面躲了两天
The night I told him his parents had died, he hid in here for two days.
等他出来的时候…
When he did come out…
就不再是小孩子了
he wasn't a boy anymore.
我们得开工了
Eh. Must get on.
是我搞砸的 对吧？
I fucked this up, didn't I?
不是
No.
你只是做了你应该做的
You did your job.
我读了你给我写的悼词
I read your obituary of me.
觉得怎么样？
And?
很感人
Appalling.
算了吧 我知道你不喜欢
Yeah, I knew you'd hate it.
我记得说了 你是「你是英国精神的榜样」
I did call you "an exemplar of British fortitude".
那一点倒是没说错
That bit was all right.
准备好了？
You ready?
在你出生之前我就准备好了
I was ready before you were born, son.
欢迎来到苏格兰
Welcome to Scotland.
你掉东西了
You dropped something.
受伤了吗？
You hurt?
只是我的骄傲被击碎了 我从来开枪就没准头
Only my pride. I never was a good shot.
他不在这里
He's not here.
他的出场方式总是这么夸张
Always got to make an entrance.
你们两个去厨房 现在就去
You two, go to the kitchen. Now.
躲到拱门的后面去！
Get behind the arch!
去祭祀洞 走隧道出去
Go to the chapel. Use the tunnel.
所有人听着！谁都不许碰她 她是我的猎物
Everyone, listen to me! Don't you dare touch her. She's mine.
你的朋友能出来打声招呼吗？
Can your friend come out and say hello?
快点 这边
Come on. This way.
我一直很讨厌这里
I always hated this place.
你暖和点了吗？
Are you getting warm?
去看看邦德是不是炸死了！
Just make sure Bond's dead!
现在就剩我和她了
Now it's me and her.
你觉得这些闹剧有什么意义吗 邦德先生？
You see what comes of all this running around, Mr. Bond?
一直这样战斗下去
All this jumping and fighting.
很累人的！
It's exhausting!
放轻松
Relax.
你需要放松
You need to relax.
哦 好吧… 妈妈在叫我
Ah, well… mother's calling.
我会给她一个告别之吻的
I'll give her a goodbye kiss for you.
天啊
Oh, my God.
当然
Of course.
我必须到这儿来
It had to be here.
必须如此
It had to be this way.
谢谢你
Thank you.
- 我不能找到别的… - 别过来
- I can't find it no… - Don't.
请别过来
Please. Don't.
你受伤了 你受伤了
You're hurt. You're hurt.
他们都对你做了什么？
What have they done to you?
解放我们两个吧
Free both of us.
用同一颗子弹…
Free both of us…
我们从此就都自由了
with the same bullet.
开枪吧
Do it.
只有你能做到
Only you can do it.
开枪吧
Do it.
啊！
Ah!
最后一只老鼠了
Last rat standing.
007 你怎么那么久才来？
007. What took you so long?
我去水里游了个泳
Well, I got into some deep water.
哦！
Oh!
我想…
I suppose it's…
这次我可能逃不掉了？
too late to make a run for it?
好吧 我就当你是在开玩笑
Well, I'm game if you are.
我至少做对了一件事
I did get one thing right.
哇哦
Wow.
我不知道你还能爬到屋顶来
I didn't even know you could come up here.
真讨厌浪费了那么好的风景
Hate to waste a view.
我能看出原因
I can see why.
我想你可以回去继续执行任务了
I thought you were going back out on active service.
我拒绝了
I declined.
是你自己说的
You said it yourself,
这工作不是所有人都能做的
fieldwork's not for everyone.
如果你听进去了 我就觉得安全多了
If it helps, I feel a lot safer.
今天宣读了她的遗嘱
Her will was read today.
她把这个留给了你
She left you this.
也许她是在用自己的方式告诉你 应该找一份文职工作了
Maybe it was her way of telling you to take a desk job.
也许正好相反
Just the opposite.
谢谢你
Thank you.
要知道 我们从来没有正式相互介绍过
You know, we've never formally been introduced.
我叫伊芙
Well, my name's Eve.
伊芙·钱班尼
Eve Moneypenny.
很高兴能与你共事 伊芙·钱班尼
Well, I look forward to our time together, Miss Moneypenny.
我也是 我很肯定以后能多刮几次胡子了
Me, too. I'm sure we'll have one or two close shaves.
早上好 007
Morning, 007.
早上好 坦纳
Good morning, Tanner.
他现在可以见你了
He'll see you now.
手臂怎么样了？
How's the arm, sir?
这个？哦 好多了
What? Oh, it's fine.
会好起来的
It'll get better.
对于一个不出任务的人来说 中枪还真是恐怖
All pretty shocking for someone unused to fieldwork.
所以 007… 有很多工作要做
So, 007… lots to be done.
你准备好回到工作岗位了吗？
Are you ready to get back to work?
乐意效劳 M
With pleasure, M.
乐意效劳
With pleasure.